

Niket Shukla

Mississauga, Ontario | 1-647-863-5646 | niketshukla@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Front-End Developer, who has worked on multiple projects under agile environment and strict timelines to create customized, visually pleasant, and user-friendly designs. Strives to emphasize on scalable and well-documented codes that can be maintained for reusability. Emphasizes on effective communication to understand client needs and preferences. Effectively materialized client preferences into straightforward and visionary products using HTML, CSS, React JS, and JavaScript.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- JavaScript
- React JS

- Responsive Web Design
- WordPress
- Heroku
- MongoDB

WORK HISTORY

WEB DEVELOPER

Tech Mahindra | Mississauga, Ontario

- Managed a team of 3 and followed end-to-end process to integrate UX design for Futuri Tether Widget
- Coded a redesigned radio widget using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript increasing its usability and performance by 30%
- Utilized React JS to add a feature in Future Tether Widget which showed trending songs that could be added by users to their favorites
- Worked in an agile-driven environment to effectively complete projects within stipulated timeframe by utilizing available resources

FRONT END DEVELOPER

05/2020 to 01/2022

Next Decipher | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Served multiple clients by communicating empathetically to understand their technical requirements, design flow, data security, and operational needs
- Developed an Admin Panel for wholesaler clients to enable them to effectively manage retailers and stock availability
- Created Safecity platform using HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, and CSS [Website: http://webapp.safecity.in/]
- Created Cylla website using multiple jQuery plugins and CSS animations [Website: http://cylla.com/]

FRONT END DEVELOPER

05/2015 to 10/2019

Creative Mantra | Mumbai, Maharashtra

• Collected, defined, and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans

02/2022 to 05/2022



Niket Shukla

Mississauga, Ontario | 1-647-863-5646 | niketshukla@gmail.com

- Developed a website and an admin panel using HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, and CSS for
 - Music learning platform which allowed users to choose a location for an inperson session, available dates, and instruments [Website: https://mymusician.com.au/home]
 - Transportation industry client, The TMS, by collaborating with PHP team to integrate the website with MySQL that helped client monitor driver activities and abide with US rules and regulations [Website: http://t-tms.com/]
- Utilized WordPress to design a website for a banking sector client, Amplifier Lab, which illustrated their smooth ecosystem [Website: https://amplifierlab.io/]
- Reviewed codes to validate structures and verify browser, device, and operating system compatibility
- Mentoring and training web developers to
 - Create sleek and innovative UI designs and write structural and semantic codes
 - Plan assigned projects, complete them before the deadline, and develop client relations

JR. FRONT END DEVELOPER

11/2013 to 04/2015

Creative Mantra | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers
- Analyzed requirements to design, develop, or improve software applications for multiple websites
- Continuously improved websites by redesigning and coding to enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical and responsive issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently

EDUCATION

Full Stack Immersion | Web Development CareerFoundry

08/2022

Master of Computer Applications | Engineering Technology Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, Mumbai

05/2013

PROJECTS

Full-Stack Immersion | CareerFoundry

08/2022

- **MyFlixStudio:** Web application created with React JS and Sass to provides users access to information regarding movies, directors, and genres
 - GitHub: https://github.com/niketshukla/myFlixStudio
- Meet App: Project aimed at building a serverless, progressive web application (PWA)
 using React JS and a test-driven development (TDD) technique that used Google
 Calendar API to fetch upcoming events
 - GitHub: https://github.com/niketshukla/MeetUp